Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Blake.
Sorry. sarge.
Pick a man. bring your kit.
Yes. sarge.
Don't dawdle.
No. sarge.
Did they feed us?
No. Just mail.
Myrtle's having puppies.
You get anything?
No.
I'm bloody starvin'. aren't you?
Thought we might get
some decent grub out here.
It was the only reason
I decided against the priesthood.
What you got there?
Ham and bread.
Where did you find that?
I have my uses.
Here.
Tastes like old shoe.
Cheer up. This time next week.
it'll be chicken dinner.
Not me.
My leave got canceled.
They say why?
No idea.
It's easier not to go back at all.
Coming through!
Something's up. Did you hear anything?
No.
Has to be the push. right?
Ten Bob says we're going up.
I'm not taking that bet.
Why? 'Cause you know I'm right?
No. because you haven't got ten Bob.
In your own time. gentlemen.
- Is there any news. sarge?
- News of what?
The big push.
It was supposed to happen weeks ago.
They told us we'd be home by Christmas.
Yes. well. sorry to disrupt
your crowded schedule. Blake.
but the brass hats
didn't fancy it in the snow.
More's the pity. sarge.
I could've done with some Turkey.
Well. I'll make sure to relay
your displeasure to command.
So. what's on the cards then.
sergeant?
The hun are up to something.
Any idea what?
No. But it's about to ruin our weekend.
Now. listen.
Erinmore is inside. so tidy yourselves up.
Never know. might be mentions
in dispatches for this one...
If you don't bugger it up.
Must be something big
if the general's here.
Lance corporals
Blake and Schofield. sir.
Which one of you is Blake?
Sir.
You have a brother.
a lieutenant in the 2nd devons?
Yes. sir. Joseph Blake. Is he...
Alive. As far as I know.
And with your help.
I'd like to keep it that way.
Sanders tells me
you're good with maps. That true?
Good enough. sir.
So...
We are here.
The 2nd devons are advancing here.
How long will it take you to get there?
I don't understand. sir.
- Sir. that land is held by the Germans.
- Germans have gone.
Don't get your hopes up.
It appears to be a strategic withdrawal.
They seem to have created a new line.
nine miles back here by the looks of it.
Colonel MacKenzie
is in command of the 2nd.
He sent word yesterday morning
he was going after the retreating Germans.
He is convinced he has them on the run.
that if he can break their lines now.
he will turn the tide.
He is wrong.
Colonel MacKenzie has not seen
these aerials of the enemy's new line.
Come around here. gentlemen.
Three miles deep.
field fortifications. defenses.
artillery the like of which
we've never seen before.
The 2nd are due to attack the line
shortly after dawn tomorrow.
They have no idea
what they're in for.
And we can't warn them.
Your orders are to get to the 2nd
at croisilles wood.
one mile southeast
of the town of ecoust.
Deliver this to colonel MacKenzie.
It is a direct order
to call off tomorrow morning's attack.
If you don't.
it will be a massacre.
We will lose two battalions.
1.600 men. your brother among them.
Do you think
you can get there in time?
Yes. sir.
Any questions?
- No. sir.
- Good.
Over to you. lieutenant.
Supplies. gentlemen.
Map. torches. grenades.
and a couple of little treats.
Leave immediately. Take this trench west
up on sauchiehall street.
Then northwest on paradise alley
at the front.
Continue along the front line
until you find the Yorks.
Give this note to major Stevenson.
He's holding the line
at the shortest span of no-man's-land.
You'll cross there.
It'll be daylight. sir.
They'll see us.
There's no need to be concerned.
You should meet no resistance.
Sir. is... is it just us?
"Down to gehenna or up to the throne.
he travels the fastest who travels alone."
- Wouldn't you say. lieutenant?
- Yes. sir. I would.
Good luck.
Blake. let's talk about this
for a minute.
Why?
Blakel
We just need to think about it.
There's nothing to think about.
It's my big brother.
- We should at least wait until it's dark.
- Erinmore said to leave immediately.
Erinmore's
never seen ho-man's-land.
We won't make it ten yards.
If we just wait...
You heard him.
He said the boche have gone.
Is that why he gave us grenades?
- Watch where you're going.
- Sorry.
All I'm saying is that we wait.
Yes. you would say that
'cause it's not your brother. is it?
Look. the last time I was told
the Germans were gone. it didn't end well.
You don't know. Blake.
You weren't there.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
You're going up the down trench.
you bloody idiot.
Orders of the general. sir.
All right.
say the boche have gone.
Nine miles would take us.
what. six hours?
Eight at the very most.
So. we've got time to wait
until the sun sets.
- It's enemy territory.
- Otherwise we'll be wide open.
We've got no idea what we're walking into.
Blake. if we're not clever about this.
no one will get to your brother.
I will.
We're here. This is the front line.
Now we need to find the Yorks.
Sorry. mate.
- Watch who you're shoving.
- Get out of the way.
Who the fuck do you think you are.
pushing wounded soldiers?
I didn't know. Let go of me!
Arsehole knocked down our sergeant.
The man's fucking wounded!
All right. I'm sorry.
All right? I'm sorry!
- We're on commission.
- Just let me through.
- Orders from the general.
Get out of the way.
All right.
Just watch where you're going.
It's bloody quiet.
Was it like this before thiepval?
Don't remember.
You don't remember the somme?
- Not really.
- Hey. mind us. Come on.
Well. you did all right out of it.
At least wear your ribbon.
Don't have it anymore.
What? You lost your medal?
Heads down. boys.
Come on. lads. Keep digging.
Stay low.
For god's sake. careful there.
You're stepping on the dead.
That's our sergeant.
Be better washing them out of this dugout
with a bloody hose.
Do you know where the Yorks are?
The next bend.
you'll be standing on top of half of them.
Shot to hell two nights ago.
Yorks?
Yes. corp.
Where's major Stevenson?
Was killed.
Couple of nights ago. corporal.
Lieutenant Leslie has command.
Where can we find him?
Next dugout.
Here.
Sir?
Lieutenant Leslie. sir?
What is it?
We have a message
from general erinmore.
- Are you our relief?
- No. sir.
Then when the fucking hell are they due?
We don't know. sir.
but we've got orders to cross here.
That is the German front line.
We know. sir.
If you'll just take the letter.
Settle a bet. What day is it?
Friday.
Friday? Well. none of us was right.
- This idiot thought it was Tuesday.
- Sorry. sir.
Are they out of their fucking minds?
One slow night. the brass think
the hun have just gone home?
Do you think they're wrong. sir?
We lost an officer and three men
two nights ago.
They were shot to bits patching up wire.
We dragged two of them back here.
Needn't have bothered...
Sir. the general is sure
the enemy have withdrawn.
- There are aerials of the new line...
- Shut up.
We fought and died
over every inch of this fucking place.
Now they suddenly give us miles.
It's a trap.
But chin up.
There's a medal in it. for sure.
Nothing like a scrap of ribbon
to cheer up a widow.
All right.
Where's the nearest way through. sir?
Our wire's a mess.
but there is a path through of sorts.
Rushworth. let him look.
Straight ahead to the left.
past the dead horses.
There's a gap directly behind them.
Useful because if it's dark.
you follow the stench.
When you get to the second wire.
look out for the bowing chap.
There's a small break just beside him.
The German line
is 150-odd yards after that.
Watch out for the craters.
They're deeper than they look.
If you fall in. there's no getting out.
This way.
Wake up. kilgour.
Bloody waste of space.
Any cover. sir?
Anywhere to jump off from?
No. The sap trench
was blown to hell weeks ago.
It was full of bodies. anyway.
Your best bet is to pop over here.
If you do get shot.
try to make it back to the wire.
We won't come after you.
not till it's dark.
And if by some fucking miracle
you do make it. send up a flare.
Don't have any. sir.
Well. get him one. kilgour.
Make yourself useful.
Yes. sir.
Through this holy unction.
may the lord pardon you your faults
and whatever sins
thou has committed.
I do hate losing these to the hun.
So. when they start shooting at you.
could you be so kind as to throw it back.
There's a good chap.
Cheerio.
You sure?
Yes.
Age before beauty.
You all right?
Look for cover.
Sap trench.
Stay still.
They're ours.
Keep going. We're halfway.
There's a gap. In the wire.
Sco.
There. That's the front line.
Fuck me.
They really have gone.
Your hand all right?
Put it through an effing German.
Patch it up.
You'll be wanking again in no time.
Wrong hand.
They're not long gone.
No good.
Blocked.
This might be a way through.
Jesus.
Look at this.
It's massive.
They built all this.
Here's our way through.
Sco.
How 'bout this?
Bloody hell.
Even their rats are bigger than ours.
What do you think's in the bags?
You cannot be that hungry.
Look at him.
Cocky little bastard.
You could eat this. though.
What is it?
Boche dog meat.
What's in the other boxes?
- What's wrong?
- Trip wire.
Don't move.
Where is it?
Goes from here to the door.
- Oh! Jesus!
- Oh. no!
Sco!
Sco?
Sco! Sco.
Sco!
Sco. Sco?
Wake up. Wake up!
Sco! Scol
stand up! Stand up!
Come on. Stand up!
Up! Up! Up!
Come on!
Stand up!
The whole thing's coming down.
You keep hold of me!
We need to keep moving.
Come on!
I can't see. I can't see!
Stop! Stop. stop. stop. stop! Stop!
It's a mine shaft.
We'll have to jump.
All right. come on.
You're going to have to jump.
Just jump.
I can't. I can't see!
You need to trust me.
Jump!
Don't let go of me! Don't let go!
Light! There's light.
Stop. stop.
Just let me stand.
Dirty bastards!
Careful. They may have left other traps.
Jesus.
Dust. So much dust in my eyes.
Here.
Have some of mine.
I wish I'd shot that rat now.
I wish you'd picked
some other bloody idiot.
- What?
- Why in god's name did you choose me?
- I didn't know what I was picking you for.
- No. you didn't.
You never know.
That's your problem.
All right. then go back.
Nothing's stopping you. You can go
all the way bloody home if you want.
Don't.
Just don't.
I didn't know what I was picking you for.
I thought they were going to send us
back up the line or for food or something.
I thought it was going to be
something easy. All right?
I never thought it would be this.
So. do you want to go back?
Just fire the fucking flare.
Up yours. lieutenant.
Do you know where we are?
Uh... ecoust is directly southeast.
And if we keep that bearing...
We should make it.
Come on. then.
Look at that.
They destroyed their own guns.
They destroyed their own trenches. too.
What do you mean?
Think they wanted us to go that way.
They wanted to bury us.
You bastard rats.
Hey. did you hear that story
about wilko?
- How he lost his ear?
- I'm not in the mood.
Keep your eyes on the trees.
Top of the Ridge.
Bet he told you it was shrapnel.
What was it. then?
Well. you know
his girl's a hairdresser. right?
And he was moaning about the lack of
bathing facilities when he wrote to her.
You remember
those rancid Jakes at arras?
Yeah.
Anyway. she sends him over this hair oll.
Smells sweet. Like golden syrup.
Wilko loves the smell. but he doesn't
want to cart it around in his pack.
So he slathers it all over his barnet.
goes to sleep.
and in the middle of the night
he wakes up.
and a rat is sitting on his shoulder.
licking the oil off his head.
Wilko panics. and he jumps up.
And when he does. the rat bites
clean through his fucking ear
- and runs off with it!
- No!
He made a hell of a fuss.
yellin'. screamin'.
The best of it was.
he'd put so much bloody oil on himself
that he couldn't wash it off.
He was like a magnet.
Rats left us alone.
but they couldn't get enough of him.
Poor bastard.
Heading back home.
I wonder what they saw.
Watch the ridgelines.
Well. that's your medal sorted. then.
What do you mean?
"Lance corporal Blake showed unusual valor
rescuing a comrade from certain death."
Blah. blah. blah.
You reckon?
I do.
Well. that'd be nice.
since you lost yours.
I didn't lose mine.
What happened to it. then?
Why do you care?
Why do you not?
I swapped it with a French captain.
- Swapped it?
- Mm-hmm.
For what?
Bottle of wine.
What did you do that for?
I was thirsty.
What a waste.
You should have
taken it home with you.
You should have given it
to your family.
Men have died for that.
If I got a medal.
I'd take it home.
- Why didn't you just take it home?
- Look. it's just a bit of bloody tin.
It doesn't make you special.
Doesn't make any difference
to anyone.
Yes. it does.
And it's not just a bit of tin.
It's got a ribbon on it.
I hated going home.
I hated it.
When I knew I couldn't stay...
When I knew I had to leave
and they might never see m...
Jesus.
They chopped them all down.
Cherries.
Lamberts.
They might be Dukes.
Hard to tell when they aren't in fruit.
What's the difference?
Well. people think there's one type.
But there's lots of them.
Cuthberts. queen annes. montmorencys.
Sweet ones. sour ones.
Why on earth
would you know this?
Mum's got an orchard back home.
Only a few trees.
This time of year.
it looks like it's been snowing.
Blossom everywhere.
And then in may.
we have to pick them.
Me and Joe.
Takes the whole day.
So. these ones all goners?
Oh. no. They'll grow again
when the stones rot.
You'll end up with more trees
than before.
It looks abandoned.
Let's hope so.
We have to make sure.
I'll take front. you take back.
Anything?
Nothing.
Did you find any food?
No.
I don't like this place.
Map says get over that Ridge
and it's a straight shot to ecoust.
Good.
Is that our friends again?
Looks like it.
Dogfight.
Who's winning?
Us. I think.
Two on one.
They got him.
- We should put him out of his misery.
- No. Get him some water. He needs water.
It's all right. It's all right.
Steady. Stay still.
Stop. Stop!
No. No. no!
You bastard!
You bloody bastard.
Oh. god. no.
Oh. god. no!
Jesus. Jesus. no!
We have to stop the bleeding.
Stop. Stop it! Stop it!
It's all right.
It's going to be all right.
We're going to stand up.
- Okay. yes. Yes.
- Right?
No. I can't. I can't. Ow!
- We have to get to an aid post.
- I can't.
- I'll carry you. It isn't very far.
- Just bring a doctor here.
We can't. We have to go together.
We're going to get up.
- Stop!
- Come on.
Please stop!
Put me down!
Put me down. you bastard. please!
Oh!
You have to try to keep moving.
Let's just sit.
- Let me sit.
- No. we can't.
We have to find the 2nd. remember?
Your brother. We have to go now.
You can start on without me.
I'll catch up.
No. You can't stay here.
We have to move. All right?
We have to move. Now. come on.
Come on!
Come on. That's it.
Come on. come on. Come on.
Your brother.
We have to find your brother.
You'll recognize him.
He looks like me.
And he's a bit older.
What are they?
Are we being shelled?
They're embers. The barn is on fire.
I've been hit.
What was it?
You were stabbed.
Am I dying?
Yes.
Yes. I think you are.
- This?
- Inside.
Will you write to my mum for me?
I will.
Tell her I wasn't scared.
Anything else?
I love them.
I wish that...
Talk to me.
Tell me you know the way.
I know the way.
I'm going to head southeast
until I hit ecoust.
I'll pass through the town
and out to the east
all the way to croisilles wood.
It'll be dark by then.
That won't bother me.
I'll find the 2nd.
I'll give them the message.
and then I'll find your brother.
Just like you. a little older.
You all right. mate?
Hey. it's all right. It's okay.
Come on. Help him.
Jesus.
What happened to him?
Was it the plane?
We saw the smoke.
Yeah.
Go and fetch his things.
Ae =o = tn
a friend?
What are you doing here?
I have an urgent message
for the 2nd devons.
Orders to stop
tomorrow morning's attack.
And where are they stationed?
Just beyond ecoust.
Come with me.
Come with me. corporal.
That's an order.
We're passing through ecoust.
We can take you some of the way.
Sir.
Oh. come on. sergeant.
Put more men at the base.
At the trunk!
It'll be heavier there.
Might be a tight squeeze.
No. you're not
going to be able to just lift it.
Pivot the front end to the left.
Jesus. they don't
make things easy. do they?
They could at least have retreated
with a bit of grace. Bastards.
Sir.
- You're not one of mine.
- No. sir.
He has an urgent message
to deliver to the 2nd devons. sir.
Can you get past it?
- No. sir.
- Oh. for god's sake.
Just move it!
There's room in the casuals' truck. sir.
- He has orders.
- Yes. yes. all right.
Come on. now.
You can get through there sideways.
How did you get here. sir?
Crossed no-man's-land
just outside bapaume.
Took us the whole night.
Bumped into a couple of hun stragglers
on the way
who made a nuisance of themselves.
- You going up to the new line?
- Attempting to.
The newfoundlands have pushed forwards
and requested reinforcements.
I'm sorry about your friend.
May I tell you something
that you probably already know?
It doesn't do to dwell on it.
No. sir.
Hop on.
Make some space there.
Come on. In you get!
All right. Here we go again. boys.
Welcome aboard the night bus
to fuck knows where.
Is that a dead dog?
- You got a fag?
- Yeah. There you go.
- Butler. oi. Carry on with that story.
- Oh. yeah.
Right. so. when we get off the train.
beaufoy comes up to us
and he's having a right go.
"Lance corporal. whatever one does.
one never lets standards slip."
Then Scott comes out the latrine.
He wipes his hand
on the back of beaufoy's jacket.
Shit all down his back.
- Was that meant to be captain beaufoy?
- Piss off. you. You can't do any better.
"Men. your rifle stocks
are an embarrassment
to the entire expeditionary force!"
- Nah.
- No.
You're both bloody awful.
You don't know.
You barely even speak the bloody language.
He's got a better grasp of it
than you. Cooke.
Go on. jondalar. Give it a go.
- Let's hear it. jonny.
- Let's hear it. Go on.
"Rossi!
Never in my 200 years as a soldier
have I seen such a sorry excuse
for a latrine pit!"
Shite. That is total shit.
Could've taken my teeth out with that.
You could do with a new set.
You got somewhere
you need to be?
- No.
- Arsehole needs driving lessons.
He should reverse. Yeah.
Try it in reverse.
Reverse!
No. Stop. Stop!
Everyone needs to get out.
All out!
- Come on!
- All right. all right.
Keep your bloody hair on.
Right.
One. two. three!
We need to get some wood.
put it under the wheels.
No. we haven't got the time.
We all need to push.
Come on. Come on!
Come on!
Please! I have to go now. Please.
All right. come on. lads.
Come on.
Come on. boys.
One. two. three.
Come on. boys!
One last push. yeah?
One. two. three!
Back in. Get back in. Go.
Are you all right?
Here. driver. how about you try to keep it
on the bloody road for a change?
Oh. piss off!
So. where are you going?
I have to get to the 2nd devons.
just past ecoust.
Why?
They're attacking at dawn.
I have orders to stop them.
How come?
- They're walking into a trap.
- How many?
Sixteen hundred.
Jesus.
Why did they send you
on your own?
They didn't.
There were two of us.
So. now it's down to you.
Yes.
You'll never make it.
Yes. I will.
Thank you.
Look at it.
Fucking look at it.
Three years fightin' over this.
We should've just
let the bastards keep it.
- I mean. who machine-guns cows?
- Huns with extra bullets.
Bastards.
Clever.
They know if they don't shoot the cow...
You will eat it.
Still bastards.
Yeah. it's not even
our bloody country.
- How long gone do you reckon they are?
- Why?
Worried we'll catch up with them?
Yeah.
Right. Be a bloody miracle at this rate.
Yeah. they're probably
right round the next corner.
Piss off. No. they're not.
Why don't they just
bloody well give up? Eh?
- Don't they wanna go home?
- They hate their wives and mothers.
And Germany must be a shithole.
They're retreatin'.
They're miles back.
Got 'em on the ropes. at least.
No. We don't.
Oh. bollocks. What's up now?
- Not another bloody tree.
- The bridge is down.
Oh. That's a shame.
Looks like I'll be getting out here.
Good luck.
Keep some of that luck
for yourself. pal.
- Think you'll be needing it.
- Good luck. mate.
Good luck. guv.
Don't balls it up.
I hope you get there.
Thank you.
The next bridge is six miles.
We'll have to divert.
I can't. sir. I don't have the time.
Of course.
Best of luck.
Thank you. sir.
Corporal?
If you do manage
to get to colonel MacKenzie...
Make sure there are withesses.
- They are direct orders. sir.
- I know.
But some men just want the fight.
Thank you. sir.
Driver! Move off!
Anglais.
Not German.
Friend.
I'm a friend.
This place. this town...
Ecoust?
Others?
No. Just me.
Only me.
I need to be somewhere.
I need to find a wood to the southeast.
Uh. trees.
Croiset?
Croisilles?
Yes.
River.
River. It go there.
Trees. Croisilles.
Shh.
Thank you.
A girl?
What is her name?
Who is her mother?
I have food.
I have these.
But you can have them.
Here. take them all.
For you and the child. Here.
Milk"?
Merci.
Bonjour.
Bonyjour.
Children? You?
Shh.
It's all right.
Continuez.
"They went to sea in a sieve. they did...
In a sieve they went to sea:
In spite of all their friends could say...
On a winter's morn. on a stormy day.
in a sieve they went to sea!
Far and few. far and few.
are the lands where the jumblies live;
their heads are green.
and their hands are blue...
And they went to sea in a sieve."
Stay. Stay. Please.
I have to go.
I'm sorry.
Shh.
Baumer?
Baumer.
Baumer!
J» I am a poor wayfaring stranger »
j» I'm traveling through
this world of woe »
j» yel there's no sickness
toil nor danger »
j in that bright land fo which I go »
j» I'm going there fo see my father »
j» I'm going there no more fo roam »
j» I'm only going over Jordan »
j» I'm only going over home j»
j I know dark clouds
will gather round me »
j» I know my way is rough and steep j»
j» but golden fields lie just before me »
j» where god's redeemed shall ever sleep »
j» I'm going home fo see my mother »
j» and all my loved ones who've gone on »
j» I'm only going over Jordan »
j» I'm only going over home j»
j» I am a poor wayfaring stranger »
j» I'm traveling through
this world of woe »
j» yel there's no sickness
toil nor danger »
j in that bright land fo which I go »
j» I'm going there fo see my father »
j» I'm going there no more fo roam »
j» I'm only going over Jordan »
j» I'm only going over home j»
D company. move out!
You all right. pal?
Where you from?
- He's probably got the wind up.
- He's not one of ours.
He's bloody soaked.
Fuck it. Let's just pick him up
and take him with us.
Have to find the devons.
What's he saying?
What's that. mate?
The devons.
I have to find the devons.
We're the devons.
You're the devons?
Yes. corp.
Why haven't you gone over?
- We're the second wave.
- They don't send us all at once.
Yeah. we're d company.
We spent the night diggin' in.
We go last.
Are you all right?
MacKenzie.
Where's colonel MacKenzie?
Well. he's down at the line.
- Which way?
- This way.
We're headed up there now.
Steady on. mate.
Where you going?
Movel
let me by!
Let me through!
Remember. follow your platoon commander.
Stay spread out
and watch for his orders.
- Where is your commanding officer?
- He's in the holding pen.
Raise your signal flags
or fire the signal flares
when you've taken your section
of the hun line.
B company. stand to.
Now listen and listen well.
On the first Mark.
a company will advance.
B company will then move
to the front line.
Sir. I have a message
from general erinmore.
- Who the fuck are you?
- The attack has been called off.
General erinmore
has called off the attack.
Balls. man. We're about to go over.
We've got them on the run!
You don't.
Please don't send your men over.
Get out of the way!
These are direct orders from army command!
Where is colonel MacKenzie?
Jesus Christ. man!
Go and see the captain!
Now. I want us up there quickly.
you understand?
- Do you understand?
- Yes. sirl
ncos collect flares and signal flags.
Keep to your stations.
Oi. Oil
Nine and ten section at the ready!
We will advance
on the first whistle blast!
The man next to you falls. keep moving.
Your orders are to break the lines.
- Where is the captain?
- He's over there.
Sir! Sir!
Captain. I have a message.
This attack is called off.
You have to stop.
Where is colonel MacKenzie?
Where is MacKenzie?
Back! Hold fast!
Sir. I have orders to stop this attack!
What?
Where is colonel MacKenzie?
He's further up the line.
How far?
Three hundred yards.
He's in a cut-and-cover.
You'll have to wait
until the first wave goes over.
No. No. I can't.
Seven platoon. 30 seconds!
You can't possibly make it that way. man!
Are you bloody insane?
What the hell are you doing.
Lance corporal?
No! No. no. no. no!
Get ready!
- Colonel MacKenzie!
- He's in there.
Two minutes!
Let me through!
Hey! Hey!
Let me through! I have to get through!
I have to see colonel MacKenzie!
- What are you doing?
- I have to stop this attack!
Colonel. we've seen flares.
Men on the left flank
have made it to the German line.
- Colonel! Colonel!
- Hold him! Hold him!
Listen to me.
Listen to me. I have a letter.
I need to see colonel MacKenzie.
There's no bloody way
you're gettin' in there!
Sergeant. send the next wave!
No!
Second wave. prepare yourselves!
- Colonel MacKenzie!
- Concentrate everything there.
This attack is not to go ahead!
You have been ordered to stop!
You have to stop!
Who the hell are you?
Lance corporal Schofield. sir. 8th.
I have orders from general erinmore
to call off this attack.
You're too late. Lance corporal.
Sir. these orders are from army command.
You have to read them.
- Shall we hold back the second wave. sir?
- No. major. Hesitate now and we lose.
Victory's only 500 yards away.
=sirl
please. read the letter.
I have heard it all before.
I'm not gonna wait until dusk or for fog.
I'm not calling back my men only
to send them out there again tomorrow.
not when we've got the bastards
on the run.
- This is their last stand.
- The Germans planned this. sir.
They've been planning it for months.
They want you to attack.
Read the letter.
- Major?
- Yes. sir?
Stand them down.
- Yes. sir.
- Call up the orderlies.
Tend the wounded.
Hold the line
in case they counter.
Yes. sir!
Stand down! Stand down!
Stand down!
- Cease fire! Cease fire!
- Stand down!
I hoped today
might be a good day.
Hope is a dangerous thing.
That's it for now. and then next week
command will send a different message.
"Attack at dawn."
There is only one way this war ends.
Last man standing.
Have someone see to your wounds.
Now. fuck off. Lance corporal.
Bearers! Stretcher bearers!
Well done. lad.
Thank you. sir.
Do you know where
lieutenant Blake is. sir?
Blake?
There were two of us.
I was sent here with his brother.
Ah.
Well. knowing lieutenant Blake.
he would have gone over with his men.
He was in the first wave.
How could I find him. sir?
You can try the casualty clearing station
behind the line.
Otherwise...
Thank you. sir.
Major hepburn. sir!
Just keep movin'.
Keep movin'. keep movin'.
Sergeant. I have to find lieutenant Blake.
Do you know where he is?
No.
Clear the way.
- Sir. is lieutenant Blake here?
- No idea.
Move along. corporal.
If you can walk. move to the triage area.
Help me!
Lieutenant Blake!
Sir. he's out.
Out of the bloody way!
Blake?
Has anyone seen lieutenant Blake?
He's hemorrhaging.
Go quickly. He needs a surgeon.
Amputation. Straight to surgery.
My leg!
I need some help here! Quickly!
I need something now!
Coming through!
All right. come on. boys.
He's taken one in the leg.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Sir.
Lieutenant Blake? Yes?
Do you need medical assistance?
No. sir. I'm from the 8th.
What the hell are you doing here?
- I was sent here to deliver a message.
- The 8th?
You must know my brother.
- I was sent here with him.
- Tom's here? Where is he?
It was very quick.
I'm sorry.
What's your name?
Schofield. sir.
Sorry. what?
It's Schofield. sir.
William Schofield.
Will.
Well. you need some food.
Get yourself to the mess tent.
If I may...
I'd like to write to your mother.
Tell her that Tom wasn't alone.
Of course.
He was...
He was a good man.
Always telling funny stories.
He saved my life.
I am glad you were with him.
Thank you. will.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm